Peigeng Jiang Graphic Designer

www.andyjpg.github.io www.behance.net/AndyPeigengJiang jiangpeigeng@gmail.com 0499 482 349

Summary

Aim to work as a Graphic Designer with two years of hands-on experience. Have experience in building a SaaS application user interface using mainly Photoshop. Providing solutions to fix web application UI issues and improve performance. Involved in many design projects, and responsible for thumbnailing, concept development, visual exploration, and concept refinement. Ability to escalate company brand awareness by identifying current creative industry trends and opportunities, and utilize it in company projects.

Work Experience

Duuet / Graphic Designer

DEC 2018 - OCT 2019, MELBOURNE

Major responsibilities include web design, digital design, and print design.

- **Situation**: The company was looking to redesign the visual appearance of its website. The new website needed to align with the current design trends and also to improve the company's brand awareness.
- Task: Research and interview with stakeholders. Ideation, validating ideas, and design refinement.
- Action: Researched company strategy, competition and the current market, and interview stakeholders. Identified target audiences and the company's goals, and pinpointed the problems that the company wanted to solve. Reviewed the visual appearance of the current website and the message from the website. Gone through the ideation process, such as research, brainstorming, and mood boarding, based on problems identified. Narrowed down ideas and conducted presentations to stakeholders for feedback. Completed design refinement based on feedback.
- Result: The visual appearance of the website was well improved compared to the previous design and had received positive feedback from stakeholders and clients. Customer return rates increased by 65%.

Project Experience

T-ONE IMAGE Website Redesign

JUL 2018 - DEC 2018, MELBOURNE

As one of the key designers in the project. Managed the project with the team throughout the design process. Collaborated with the technical team in website implementation Link: www.t-oneimage.com.au

DUUET Website Redesign

JAN 2018 - JUN 2018, MELBOURNE

Successfully redesigned Duuet Wedding Photography Website. Responsible for research, concept creation, idea validation and design refinement. The new website has successfully implemented and customer return rates has increased by 65%

Link: www.duuet.com.au

Skills

Design: Illustration & UI graphics •
Photoshop • Print layout design with
InDesign • UI mock ups with Sketch

Prototyping: Web prototyping using Adobe XD • Ineractive demo with HTML / CSS / JS

Research: Data analysis • Design trends analysis

Collaboration: Self Starter • Flexible •
Detail oriented • Communicative • Time
management • Teamwork •
Problem-solving

T-ONE IMAGE / Graphic Designer

SEP 2017 - DEC 2018, MELBOURNE

Successfully coordinate graphic design projects from concept through completion. Work closely with key stakeholders to create visions, conceive designs and consistently meet deadlines and requirements. Responsible for variety of works such as manage web content, print design and digital design.

- **Situation**: The company needed to produce print designs for the wedding photography exhibition, given 3 weeks timeframe.
- Task: Coordinate with photographers and managers. Produce design through concept to completion.
- Action: Researched recent trends in the wedding photography industry. Identified the current company's unique photograph style with senior photographers and selected iconic photos as a base design style. Conceptualized design, drafted and produced initial versions of the design. Presented findings and initial design to managers and key stakeholders. Refined design upon the feedback received.
- Result: Successfully produced print design that fits the company's goal and style, within the tight schedule. Attracted many clients in the wedding photography exhibition and received positive feedback from managers and other stakeholders.
- **Situation**: The company demanded a visual-based website design for its new project. The website was mainly for exploration of new field within the market and required a live demo of the website.
- Task: Review documents of new projects and manage the design process. Produce web design with an interactive interface.
- Action: Started with identifying the project goal, value, and target audience. Researched design trends and identified problems that need to be solved, proposed findings to the team. Drafted design and produced website visual design through photoshop. Obtained feedback from design presentations with key stakeholders. Refined design and implemented an interactive demo on Adobe XD.
- Result: Received positive feedback from stakeholders with a well implemented interactive demo. Produced high-quality web design within a month, and commented by colleagues about strong skill in Adobe suite.

PR ASIA / Graphic Designer Intern

JAN 2016 - DEC 2016, MELBOURNE

Major responsibilities include collaborate with senior design in design projects.

Education

Deakin University / Bachelor of Design

JUL 2016 - JUL 2017, MELBOURNE

- **GPA**: 3.04 / 4.00 (Core GPA: 3.16)
- Honors/Awards: Graduate with High Distinction (2017)
- Relevant Coursework: Computer and Art Design, Web design, UI and UX design, branding

Holmesglen Institute / Diploma of Graphic Design

JAN 2014 - JUL 2016, MELBOURNE

• Relevant Coursework: Typographic design, Digital design, Branding and identity design, Interactive design